<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2023 Oliver Hamlet -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.loot.loot</id>
  <url type="homepage">https://loot.github.io</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/loot/loot/issues</url>
  <url type="faq">https://loot.github.io/docs/help/LOOT-FAQs</url>
  <url type="help">https://loot.readthedocs.io/en/stable/</url>
  <url type="translate">https://github.com/loot/loot/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md#translating-loot</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/loot/loot</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/loot/loot/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>

  <name>LOOT</name>
  <summary>Modding utility for some Elder Scrolls and Fallout games</summary>

  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <description>
    <p>
      LOOT is a plugin load order optimisation tool for TES III: Morrowind, TES IV: Oblivion, TES V: Skyrim, TES V: Skyrim Special Edition, Skyrim VR, Fallout 3, Fallout: New Vegas, Fallout 4 and Fallout 4 VR. It is designed to assist mod users in avoiding detrimental conflicts, by automatically calculating a load order that satisfies all plugin dependencies and maximises each plugin&apos;s impact on the user&apos;s game.
    </p>
    <p>
      LOOT also provides some load order error checking, including checks for requirements, incompatibilities and cyclic dependencies. In addition, it provides a large number of plugin-specific usage notes, bug warnings and Bash Tag suggestions.
    </p>
    <p>
      Although LOOT is able to calculate the correct load order positions for the vast majority of mods without any user input, some plugins are designed to load at certain positions in a load order, and LOOT may be unable to determine this from the plugins themselves. As such, LOOT provides a mechanism for supplying additional plugin metadata so that it may sort them correctly.
    </p>
    <p>
      LOOT is intended to make using mods easier, and mod users should still possess a working knowledge of mod load ordering.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.loot.loot.desktop</launchable>

  <translation type="gettext">loot</translation>

  <provides>
    <binary>LOOT</binary>
  </provides>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source" width="1079" height="800">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loot/loot/0.21.0/docs/images/main.png</image>
      <caption>The LOOT main window</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.21.0" date="2023-09-17">
      <description>
        <p>This is the first release to be made available on Linux.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://loot.readthedocs.io/en/0.21.0/app/changelog.html#id1</url>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
